<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0CR3/rng/docbookxi.rng"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="installation" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<info>
		<title>Download, Installation &amp; Configuration</title>
	</info>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>Download</primary>
		<secondary>Installation</secondary>
	</indexterm>	
    
    <para>Please follow the steps for the best user experience:
    	<procedure xml:id="proc.pre">
    		<step><para>Download LaTEX for Windows on: <link xlink:href="https://www.tug.org/texlive/acquire-netinstall.html">https://www.tug.org/texlive/acquire-netinstall.html</link>.</para></step>
    		<step><para>Download the App on: <link xlink:href="https://saigkill.github.io/latex_curriculum_vitae-dotnet/latex_curriculum_vitae.exe">https://saigkill.github.io/latex_curriculum_vitae-dotnet/latex_curriculum_vitae.exe</link>.</para></step>
    		<step><para>Move the executable to the place, where you want (eg: Desktop or Userdirectory). The app will be executed there, without any installation.</para></step>
    	</procedure>
    	</para>

	<section xml:id="installation-firstrun">
		<info>
			<title>User settings</title>
		</info>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>User settings</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<para>After launching <productname>latex_curriculum_vitae</productname> the first time, it opens a User settings window, where you can place your information.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="fo">
				<imagedata fileref="UserSettings.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata fileref="UserSettings.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>The Email settings are mandatory in case of you wish to send out the emails directly. The needed information about the SMTP host you get in your email-providers settings.</para>
		<para>The <guibutton>Save</guibutton> Button saves your changes and closes the window. The <guibutton>Close</guibutton> just closes the window without any changes in the config file. If you are using the button: <mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="fo">
				<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject> then you forwarded to the online documentation (this one).</para>		
		<para>During the firstrun <productname>latex_curriculum_vitae</productname> installs a bunch of
			needed files at: <filename>%appdata%/latex_curriculum_vitae</filename>. In my case the
			full path looks like:
				<filename>C:\Users\Sasch\Appdata\Roaming\latex_curriculum_vitae</filename>. You also
			can type in Windows Explorers addressfield
				<filename>%appdata%/latex_curriculum_vitae</filename>.</para>
		    <para>The AppData directory hold all relevant data for building your job application. After the copy process is done, close the App, because you have sone things to do before producing a job application.</para>
		<para>Your Appdata directory looks like:</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="fo">
				<imagedata fileref="AppDataDir.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata fileref="AppDataDir.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Let's show what is important there. The first Directoty contains 3 directories (Bibliography, Certificates and Certificates of Employment). The Bibliography directory only holds a file called <filename>bibliography.bib</filename>. This is a standard bibfile from Latex, currently filled with my 
			publications. Feel free to replace their with yours. The second directory <filename>Certificates</filename> are empty. In that directory, you can place all your certificates (maybe a further education or a course what you finished). The third directory is <filename>Certificates of Employment</filename> is reserved
		for that kind of certificates, what you become from your boss after ending your job. For the <filename>Certificates</filename> and the <filename>Certificates of Employment</filename> are some things important.</para>
		<example xml:id="ex.sorting">
			<title>Sorting the examples</title>
			<remark>In the most countries you have to order your material anti-chronologic. That means the first certificate is the last one, ordered to the oldest certificate. To provide this, you have to add a Prefix for each certificate. Lets say, you have three certificates from jobs in 2018, 2019 and 2020. Then prefix the certificates so:
			</remark><itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>1_your_2018job.pdf</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>2_your_2019job.pdf</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>3_your_2020job.pdf</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<remark>Your mention is right: The next will be a 4_your_2021job.pdf. By preparing the files in that case, i can do a reverse ordering by rhe app itself.</remark>
		</example>
		<para>Now we looking the other directories. We have a <filename>Curriculum_Vitae</filename> directory. And it contains a predefined LaTEX file for the curriculum vitae called <filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename>. Then we have a file <filename>friggeri-cv.cls</filename>. As you maybe expect, this
		is the class file for producing the curriculum vitae. The <filename>Letter of Application</filename> directory holds the <filename>letter_of_application.tex</filename> file, what we use for producing the letter of application. The <filename>Pictures</filename> directory contains some icons for building the cv and also a
		<filename>signature.png</filename> and a <filename>userpic.jpg</filename>. Just replace them with your own signature file and userpic.</para>
		<para>In your AppData directory we also have two other files. Per default, the <filename>JobApplications.csv</filename> is empty, and will be filled during the creating part of the job application. You can open the csv file with a Excel or LibreOffice Calc.The <filename>personal_data.tex</filename> holds your personal data. As you set your preferences in the User Settings Window, this file was
			produced. It will be newly created after each iteration. <important><para>So if you want to change your data, use the User Settings Window.</para></important></para>
	</section>

	<section xml:id="preparing-latex-files">
		<info>
			<title>Preparing the latex files</title>
		</info>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Preparing Latex</primary>
		</indexterm>
		
		<para>
			As already written, we have the LaTEX files <filename>letter_of_application.tex</filename> and <filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename>. You have to modify it for your needs. Also it's possible to use your own tefiles. It is just important to save they as <filename>letter_of_application.tex</filename> and 
			<filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename> in the prepared directories. This app produces two files, for compiling the job application: the first <filename>personal_data.tex</filename> you already heard. It looks in my case:
		</para>
		<screen>
\def\firstname{Sascha}
\def\familyname{Manns}
\def\mystreet{Maifeldstraße 10}
\def\mycity{56727 Mayen}
\def\myphone{+49-000-0000000}
\def\myemail{Sascha.Manns@outlook.de}
\def\myblog{http://saschamanns.de}			
		</screen>
		<para>So if you just add a <code>\input{$HOME/AppData/Roaming/latex_curriculum_vitae/personal_data.tex}</code> to your c<filename>Curriculum_vitae.tex</filename> you can use the newly defined macros. Each place in the document where you write <code>\firstname</code>, LaTEX sets your firstname. If you prepare a own
			cv, and want to add a image reference or link with a image, you have to set the full path like: <code>\href{https://www.facebook.com/sascha.manns}{sascha.manns}\includegraphics[width=0.4cm]{$HOME/AppData/Roaming/latex_curriculum_vitae/Pictures/facebook.png}</code>.</para>
		<para>The second mentioned file is called <filename>application_details.tex</filename>. It will also generated by the app during the creating process. It looks like:</para>
		<screen>
\def\jobtitle{Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung}
\def\company{XYZ GmbH}
\def\contact{Mr. Bean}
\def\street{Street 2}
\def\city{A City}
\def\salutation{Dear Mr. Bean,}
\def\subject{Application as Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung}
\def\addressstring{XYZ GmbH\\Mr. Bean \\Street 2\\56068 A City}			
		</screen>
		<para>Because that file will jsut be created inside the temporary directory, where the compilation happens, you just can use <code>\input{./application_details.tex}</code> to use the macros defined there.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
