<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0CR3/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="cha.installation"
	xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<info>
		<title>Download, Install &amp; Configure</title>
	</info>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>Download</primary>
		<secondary>Installation</secondary>
	</indexterm>

	<section xml:id="sec.preperations">
	<info>
		<title>Where to Start</title>
	</info>
	<para>Please use the following steps for the best user experience:
		<procedure xml:id="proc.preperations">
			<step>
				<para>Download LaTEX for Windows on: <link xlink:href="https://www.tug.org/texlive/acquire-netinstall.html">https://www.tug.org/texlive/acquire-netinstall.html</link>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Download the Latex Cirriculum Vitae app on: <link xlink:href="https://github.com/saigkill/latex_curriculum_vitae-dotnet/releases">https://github.com/saigkill/latex_curriculum_vitae-dotnet/releases</link>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Move the executable to a chosen location on your computer (for example, the desktop or Userdirectory). The app will be executed there, without any further installation.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Launch the app.</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
	</para>
	</section>	

	<section xml:id="sec.firstrun">
		<info>
			<title>User Settings</title>
		</info>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>User Settings</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<para xml:id="par.usersettings">When you launch <productname>latex_curriculum_vitae</productname> the first time, a User Settings window will open. Here you can fill in your personal information.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="fo">
				<imagedata fileref="UserSettings.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata fileref="UserSettings.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>All settings in this window are mandatory.</para>
		<para>If you want to shorten your links before they are saved, you can use BitLy. Get a token via <link xlink:href="https://bitly.is/accesstoken"
			xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://bitly.is/accesstoken</link> and place it in the "BitLy Token" field.</para>
				
		<para>The <guibutton>Save</guibutton> button saves your changes and closes the window. The <guibutton>Close</guibutton> button closes the window without applying changes to the config file. If you are click the button: <mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="fo">
				<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject> you will be forwarded to this online documentation.</para>
	<para>During the first run of <productname>latex_curriculum_vitae</productname> a collection of required files will be installed 
			to: <filename>%appdata%/latex_curriculum_vitae</filename>. As an example, on my computer the full
			file path appears as:
		<filename>C:\Users\Sasch\Appdata\Roaming\latex_curriculum_vitae</filename>. Alternatively, if you  
			type <filename>%appdata%/latex_curriculum_vitae</filename> in the Windows Explorer address field, Windows Explorer will direct you to the file path location.
	</para>
	<para>The AppData directory holds all relevant data for building your job application.</para> 
	<para>After required files have been automatically installed and your user information has been updated, 
	close the app and complete the following directory set-up before creating your first application.</para>
	<para>Your AppData directory will look like this:</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject role="fo">
			<imagedata fileref="AppDataDir.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
		</imageobject>
		<imageobject role="html">
			<imagedata fileref="AppDataDir.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
		</imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
	<para>The Appendix directory contains 3 sub-directories:
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Bibliography</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Certificates</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Certificates of Employment</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	 The Bibliography directory only holds a file called <filename>bibliography.bib</filename>. 
		This is a standard bibfile from LaTEX, currently containing my publications. Feel free to replace these publications with your own. 
		<important><para>
		If you are not using this feature, comment out the sections <code>\addbibresource{bibliography.bib}</code> and:		
		<screen>
\section{Publikationen}
\printbibsection{article}{Artikel}
\printbibsection{book}{Bücher} 
\printbibsection{misc}{other publications}
		</screen>
		 of the <filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename> file, by placing a % symbol at the beginning of each specified line.
		</para></important>
		The <filename>Certificates</filename> directory is empty. In this directory, you can place copies of all 
		your certificates (for example, certificates from further education or a completed course). The <filename>Certificates of Employment</filename> directory is reserved
		for that specific type of certificate, such as a letter of recommendation. To set-up the <filename>Certificates</filename> and <filename>Certificates of Employment</filename> directories, some additional features are important.</para>
		<para>In most countries, you have to order your material anti-chronologic. That means the first certificate displayed is the oldest one, and the remainder are ordered from oldest to newest certificate. To create this structure, you need to add a prefix to each certificate file name. 
			For example, if you have three certificates from jobs dated 2018, 2019, and 2020, then the certificate file prefixes would be named:</para>	
	<example xml:id="ex.sorting">
		<title>Certificate File Naming Example</title>		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>1_your_2018job.pdf</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>2_your_2019job.pdf</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>3_your_2020job.pdf</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>		
	</example>
	<para>The next file is theoretically a 4_your_2021job.pdf. By preparing the file names this way, you can easily reverse the order in the app itself.</para>
	<para>The <filename>Curriculum_Vitae</filename> directory contains a predefined LaTEX file called <filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename>, 
		and a file named <filename>friggeri-cv.cls</filename>. As you might expect, these
		are the class files for producing the curriculum vitae.</para> 
	<para>The <filename>Letter of Application</filename> directory contains the <filename>letter_of_application.tex</filename> file, which is used to produce the application letter.</para> 
	<para>The <filename>Pictures</filename> directory contains some icons for building the CV, a
		<filename>signature.png</filename>, and a <filename>userpic.jpg</filename>. You can replace these files with your personal signature file and userpic by writing over the delivered one. Note: Keep the original file names.</para>
	<para>There are two other files found in your AppData directory. By default, the <filename>JobApplications.csv</filename> is empty on the first run, and will be populated during the job application creation. You can open this CSV file 
		using Excel or LibreOffice Calc.<important><para>If you want to open and change the CSV file, make a copy first, and leave the original untouched.</para></important> The <filename>personal_data.tex</filename> contains your personal data. After you set your information in the User Settings Window, this file will
			be produced.<important>
		<para>This TEX file will be re-created after each iteration. If you need to change your information, use the User Settings Window.</para>
	</important>
</para>
</section>

<section xml:id="sec.latex-files">
<info>
	<title>Preparing the LaTEX Files</title>
</info>
<indexterm>
	<primary>Preparing LaTEX</primary>
</indexterm>

<para>
			As previously noted, the app directory contains two LaTEX files: <filename>letter_of_application.tex</filename> and <filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename>. Both files will be updated with your personal information. Note, it is possible to use your own TEX files, 
			but they must be saved as <filename>letter_of_application.tex</filename> and <filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename> in the correct directories.</para> 
			<para>When run, the app produces two files for compiling the 
			job application. The first, <filename>personal_data.tex</filename>, was discussed above. As an example, in my case, it looks like this:
</para>
<screen>
\def\firstname{Sascha}
\def\familyname{Manns}
\def\mystreet{Maifeldstraße 10}
\def\mycity{56727 Mayen}
\def\myphone{+49-000-0000000}
\def\myemail{Sascha.Manns@outlook.de}
\def\myblog{http://saschamanns.de}			
</screen>
<para>If you add an <code>\input{personal_data.tex}</code> to your <filename>curriculum_vitae.tex</filename>, you can use the newly defined macros. For each place in the 
		document where you write <code>\firstname</code>, LaTEX will set your first name.</para> 
		<para>If you prepare your own CV, and want to add an image reference or link with an image, you have to set the full path as: 
	<code>\href{https://www.facebook.com/sascha.manns}{sascha.manns}\includegraphics[width=0.4cm]{$HOME/AppData/Roaming/latex_curriculum_vitae/Pictures/facebook.png}</code>.
</para>
<para>The second file generated by the app is called <filename>application_details.tex</filename>. It will look something like this:</para>
<screen>
\def\jobtitle{Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung}
\def\company{XYZ GmbH}
\def\contact{Mr. Bean}
\def\street{Street 2}
\def\city{A City}
\def\salutation{Dear Mr. Bean,}
\def\subject{Application as Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung}
\def\addressstring{XYZ GmbH\\Mr. Bean \\Street 2\\56068 A City}			
</screen>
<para>Because this file will only be created inside a temporary directory, you can use <code>\input{application_details.tex}</code> for the macros defined there.</para>
</section>
</chapter>
