<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0CR3/rng/docbookxi.rng"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="cha.usage" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<info>
			<title>How to Use <productname>latex_curriculum_vitae</productname></title>
		</info>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>Usage</primary>
	</indexterm>

	<section xml:id="sec.mainmenue">
		<info>
			<title>The Main Menu</title>
		</info>
		<para>This section will now show you how the app works in practice. Please follow the Installation Guide in Chapter 2.0 before continuing.</para>
		<procedure xml:id="proc.mainmenue">
			<step>
				<para>Launch Latex Curriculum Vitae from your desktop.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>The user interface opens, displaying:</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject role="fo">
						<imagedata fileref="MainWindow.png" width="80%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
					<imageobject role="html">
						<imagedata fileref="MainWindow.png" width="80%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</step>
		</procedure>
		<para>You have two options. To start writing your application, you can click on the button "Write your Job-Application" and follow the documentation below <link linkend="sec.write_application"/>. 
		If you want to see or change your user settings, select "View or Change User Settings" and read more on <link linkend="par.usersettings"/>. Currently, the database feature of this app is not supported. Follow on GitHub for release updates.</para>
	</section>

	<section xml:id="sec.write_application">
		<info>
			<title>Write Your Application</title>
		</info>
		<para>Use this windwo to write your job application. To begin:</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="fo">
				<imagedata fileref="WriteJobApplication.png" width="80%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata fileref="WriteJobApplication.png" width="80%" align="center"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<procedure xml:id="proc.GUI">			
			<step>
				<para>In the "Job Title" box, place the title of your new
					job.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>The company name is already known, then type it in the "Company Name" box.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>You can include more information about the company in the address boxes. If you do not know the street, zip code, and city, you can leave it blank.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Now you can enter the information for the contact person. If you do not have a name, then simply leave this box blank. In this situation the app will write "To whom it may concern" as a salutation (this salutation will also be used if you select a gender of "Other/Neutral"). 
				In all other cases the app produces a "Dear Mr. Bean" or "Dear Mrs. Bean" salutation.</para>
				<para>The "Application details" range are pure optional. In the "URL" field you can add the job offer URL. It will be placed in the CSV file for future reference.</para>
				<para>If you set the checkbox "Initiative application", the Subject from the <filename>letter_of_applicaton.tex</filename> will be changed from "Application as" to "Initiative application as".</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>There are two options for using the app. In the case where you enter a email address and click <guibutton>Generate</guibutton>, the app will compile all files and email it directly (if you have set the SMTP settings 
				in the Installation Guide. See <link linkend="par.usersettings"/>) with you in BCC. If you leave the email box blank and click 
					<guibutton>Generate</guibutton>, the app will also compile all files, but in this case will open Windows Explorer showing the compile folder (<filename>AppData/Local/Temp/latex_curriculum_vitae</filename>) directory.  
					Every file that you can see in this directory will be deleted with each new iteration; however, you now have the option to upload the files yourself to a job application website.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Now your application is done! You can now proceed to writing another.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>By clicking on <guibutton>Close</guibutton> you will exit the app. If you are select the button: <mediaobject>
					<imageobject role="fo">
						<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
					<imageobject role="html">
						<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject> you will be forwarded to this online documentation.</para>
			</step>			
		</procedure>
	</section>
</chapter>
