<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0CR3/rng/docbookxi.rng"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="usage" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<info>
		<title>Usage</title>
	</info>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>Usage</primary>
	</indexterm>

	<section xml:id="usage-configfile">
		<info>
			<title>How to use <productname>latex_curriculum_vitae</productname></title>
		</info>
		<para>If you already prepared the things in the Installation chapter, we can show how it works in the practice.</para>
		<procedure xml:id="proc-GUI">
			<step>
				<para>Launch Latex Curriculum Vitae from your selected place.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Now opens the user interface:</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject role="fo">
						<imagedata fileref="MainWindow.png" width="25%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
					<imageobject role="html">
						<imagedata fileref="MainWindow.png" width="25%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>In the jobtitle box, you have to place the title of your new
					job.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>The company name is already known, then you have to type it there.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>If you are not knowing the street, zip code and city, you can leave it blank.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Now we can place the name of the contact person. If we dont have any name, then we just can leave it blank. In that case the app will write "Dear Sir or Madam". That also will be used, if you choose the Gender "Unknown". In all other cases it produces a "Dear Mr. Bean" or "Dear Mrs Bean".</para>
				<para>The "Apllication details" range are pure optional. In the "URL" field you can add the job offer url. It will be placed in the CSV file, what already was discussed.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Now we have two options, to use the app. In case of you are entering a email address, and click on <guibutton>Generate</guibutton>, the app compiles all stuff and send it directly out (if you have set the SMTP settings in the installation part) with you in BCC. If you leave it blank and click on 
					<guibutton>Generate</guibutton>, the app also compiles all stuff, but in this case it opens the WIndows Explorer with the <filename>AppData/Local/Temp/latex_curriculum_vitae</filename> directory. This is the compile folder. All what you can see there will be deleted each new iteration. But now you have 
					the option to upload the files to a job application website.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>By clicking on <guibutton>Configuration</guibutton>, the app launches the User Settings Window. And <guibutton>Close</guibutton> will exiting the app. If you are using the button: <mediaobject>
					<imageobject role="fo">
						<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
					<imageobject role="html">
						<imagedata fileref="F1Help_16x.png" width="5%" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject> then you forwarded to the online documentation (this one).</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>There just place the surname. It uses the contacts sex to create the Name. If
					you haven't a name, leave it blank. Then the program uses "Sehr geehrte Damen
					und Herren".</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Now place the email address. It will used for sending out the CV.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Currently I have defined 3 kinds of targets. sudoku, support and kfm, Then it
					customize the motivational letter to it-documentation, it-support or jobs as
					merchant.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>The last field is for a URL. If you have a specific URL with the job-offer,
					you can place it there, and can return later.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>After clicking on <guibutton>Go!</guibutton> it builds the curriculum vitae
					with LaTEX. If this build is succeeded, the PDF will be shown by your preferred
					PDF-Viewer.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>After clicking on <guibutton>yes</guibutton> it sends out the application and
					adds the information to the CSV file.</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
	</section>
</chapter>
